Ziyu Li

@ zli17nl@gmail.com

+31 630983914

y ziyuli_li

ziyuli.me

zLizy



Personal Statement

Graduated from Delft University of Technology, ranked 47th in QS, she delves into research focusing on database and machine learning. During her academic journey, she published in top journals, i.e., IEEE Transactions on Knowledge and Data Engineering (TKDE) and top conference in database, i.e., IEEE International Conference on Data Engineering (ICDE). She actively participates in international conferences and is also committed to academic activities and student guidance. She is currently working as a postdoc and researcher in the Web Information Systems group of Delft University of Technology. Her research focuses on structured metadata representation and the utilization of it to improve the efficiency and effectiveness of machine learning workflows.

Education

2019 - 2024 Delft University of Technology Computer Science

Delft, Netherlands

Supervisors: Prof. Alessandro Bozzon, Asterios Katsifodimos

Research: Databases, Machine Learning

Dissertation: On the Utility of Metadata to Optimize ML Workflows

2017 - 2019 Delft University of Technology Computer Science

Delft, Netherlands

Supervisor: Huijuan Wang

Thesis: Diffusion Based Temporal Network Embedding for Link Prediction

2013 - 2017 | South China University of Technology Computer Engineering

Guangzhou, China

Experience

2024.2 - Now

Postdoc researcher Delft University of Technology

Delft, Netherlands

• Web Information Systems (WIS) group

2019 - 2024	PhD candidate	Delft University of T	Technology
	Delft, Netherlands		
	Web Information Systems (WIS) group		
2018.5 - 2018.8	Data Analyst Intern	Corbion	Amsterdam, Netherlands
2016.7 - 2016.9	Intern	South China University of Technology	
	Communication & Computer Network Lab of GuangDong		



自 Publications

Conference

- Ziyu Li, Hilco van der Wilk, Danning Zhan, Megha Kloska, Alessandro Bozzon, and Rihan Hai. "Model Selection with Model Zoo via Graph Learning" In 2024 IEEE 40th International Conference on Data Engineering (ICDE), IEEE, 2024.
- Ziyu Li, Mariette Schönfeld, Wenbo Sun, Marios Fragkoulis, Rihan Hai, Alessandro Bozzon, and Asterios Katsifodimos. "Optimizing ML Inference Queries Under Constraints." In International Conference on Web Engineering, pp. 51-66. Cham: Springer Nature Switzerland, 2023.
- Ziyu Li, Henk Kant, Rihan Hai, Asterios Katsifodimos, and Alessandro Bozzon. "Macaroni: Crawling and Enriching Metadata from Public Model Zoos." In International Conference on Web Engineering, pp. 376-380. Cham: Springer Nature Switzerland, 2023.
- Rihan Hai, Christos Koutras, Andra Ionescu, Ziyu Li, Wenbo Sun, Jessie Van Schijndel, Yan Kang, and Asterios Katsifodimos. "Amalur: Data integration meets machine learning." In 2023 IEEE 39th International Conference on Data Engineering (ICDE), pp. 3729-3739. IEEE, 2023.
- Ziyu Li, Mariette Schönfeld, Rihan Hai, Alessandro Bozzon, and Asterios Katsifodimos. "Optimizing machine learning inference queries for multiple objectives." In 2023 IEEE 39th International Conference on Data Engineering Workshops (ICDEW), pp. 74-78. IEEE, 2023.
- Ziyu Li, Hai, Rihan, Bozzon, Alessandro, & Katsifodimos, Asterios (2022, July). "Metadata Representations for Queryable ML Model Zoos". In ICML, DataPerf Benchmarking Data for Data-Centric AI.
- Ziyu Li, Asterios Katsifodimos, Alessandro Bozzon, and Geert Jan Houben. 'Complex Event Processing on Real-time Video Streams." In PhD@ VLDB. 2020.

Journal

• Ziyu Li, Wenbo Sun, Danning Zhan, Yan Kang, Lydia Chen, Alessandro Bozzon, and Rihan Hai. "Amalur: Data integration meets machine learning." IEEE Transactions on Knowledge and Data Engineering (2024).

- **Ziyu Li**, Henk Kant, Rihan Hai, Asterios Katsifodimos, Marco Brambilla, and Alessandro Bozzon. "Metadata Representations for Queryable Repositories of Machine Learning Models." *IEEE Access* (2023).
- Xiuxiu Zhan, **Ziyu Li**, Masuda N., et al. "Susceptible-infected-spreading-based network embedding in static and temporal networks" [J]. EPJ Data Science, 2020, 9(1): 30.

Presentation and Poster

Presentation		
2023.	23rd International Conference on Web Engineering (ICWE)	
2023.	2nd International Workshop on Databases and Machine (DBML)@ICDE	
2022.	39th International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML)	
2021.	The Dutch Seminar on Data Systems Design (DSDSD)	
2020.	46th International Conference on Very Large Databases (VLDB)	
Doctor		

Poster

2023.12	20th The Dutch-Belgian DataBase Day (DBDBD)
2023.6	23rd International Conference on Web Engineering (ICWE)
2021.12	18th The Dutch-Belgian DataBase Day (DBDBD)

Q Activities

2023.9 - 2024.5	3rd DBML workshop @ICDEAs a chair with Prof. Dr. Carsten Binnig and Dr. Gerardo Vitagliano	
2023.5	Review paper for IEEE Transactions on Parallel and Distributed Systems	
2020 - 2024	Coaching in total 6 master students, with one obtaining 9 grade (out of 10) and two 8.5	